Steel, Johannes; Papers ger088
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Johannes Steel Papers
1933-1981
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger088
0.8 cubic ft.
The collection contains correspondence, 1934-1978, and clippings of newspaper articles, 1933-1981, the earlier articles discuss events in Nazis Germany. Steel wrote the column "Johannes Steel on Wall Street" for the New York Post which provides information on investing.
Collection X
Biographical / Historical
Johannes Steel (birth name Herbert Stahl) was born in Elberfeld, Germany in 1906. Steel studied in Heideiberg, Oxford, Geneva, and Berlin. Steel came to the United States in the 1930s and became a foreign editor of the New York Post where he was known for his column, "Johannes Steel on Wall Street." Steel was also a political commentator for the WMCA and WHN radio stations. Steel ran for a spot in the House of Representatives in 1946, but was not elected. Steel died on November 30, 1988 and was survived by his wife.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence and newspaper articles written by Johannes Steel which convey events in Nazi Germany. The collection also contains columns written by Steel that focus on investing.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically. There are no series.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection was donated by Johannes Steel in 1981.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is unrestricted.
Steel, Johannes, 1906-1988; World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees; Newspapers--Sections, columns, etc.--Economics; Nazis--Press coverage--United States; Newspaper clippings; Correspondence; Economics
- Articles by Johannes Steel (1 of 2), 1933-1934 (Flat-file 1)
- Articles by Johannes Steel (2 of 2), 1933-1934 (Flat-file 2)
- Articles by Johannes Steel, 1933-1935; 1951-1952; Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Articles by Johannes Steel, 1934-1935 (Flat-file 3)
- Articles with Reference to Johannes Steel, 1934-1936; 1945-1947; 1980; Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Biographical Material, 1943; 1970-1977; 1980-1982; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Biographical Material, Undated (Flat-file 4)
- Bowery Branch Newsletter, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Conference of Public Affairs, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Congressional Election, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence: Alan Magary and Arthur F. Burns, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence: General, 1934; 1969-1971; 1976 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence: General, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence: General, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence: John Chabot Smith, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence: Leslie Reade, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Foreign Policy Association, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- The Future of Europe by Johannes Steel, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Scope and Contents
  Advertisements.
- Hitler as Frankenstein by Johannes Steel, 1933; Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Book Reviews and Advertisements.
- Information About Companies and Industries, 1974; 1976-1978; Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Invitations, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Lafferty, Harwood, and Partners Ltd., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Materials About the Ship That Stood Still, by Leslie Reade, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Material Concerning Hotel-Casino Project in Atlantic City, New Jersey, 1977; Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Murder in Wall Street, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Near East Report, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- New York Stockbrokers Forum, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Newspaper Clippings, 1933; 1942; 1976-1977; Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Newspaper Column from the Colorado Springs Sun, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Newspaper Column "Global Gossip" from The Daily Compass, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Newspaper Column, "Johannes Steel Checks Out Wall Street," from the Las Vegas Sun, 1977; 1981 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Newspaper Column, "On Wall Street," from the Waterbury Republican, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Newspaper Column, "Steel Filings," from the New York Post, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Overseas Press Club Bulletin, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Overseas Press Club Bulletin, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Overseas Press Club of America Bulletin, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Overseas Press Club of America, Inc., 1975-1976; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Radio Station, WMCA, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Resort Network, Inc., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Society of the Silurians, Inc., 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)